Finding Aid for the Charles G. Gant California Democratic Council Records LSC.1073
UCLA Library Special Collections
Charles G. Gant California Democratic Council Records
1960-1967
UCLA Library Special Collections
Gant, Charles G.
LSC.1073
5.0 Linear Feet (10 boxes)
Charles Green Gant (b.1916) served as president of the Northridge Democratic Club (1958) and the Santa Ana Democratic Club (1960-61), California Democratic Council (CDC) director for the 35th congressional district (1963-65), was the manager of the 1964 CDC convention, and served as a member of the Democratic County Central Committee of Orange County. In 1965, he was elected as the first southern vice-president of CDC, but resigned with other board members several months later because of insoluble conflicts with CDC president Simon Casady. Later, he helped form, and then head, Democrats of Southern California. The collection consists of correspondence, clippings, and printed material relating to the activities of the California Democratic Council and former southern vice-president, Charles G. Gant. Includes files on the Simon Casady political disputes, 1965, as well as materials related to Gant's political activities in Orange County, California.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Charles G. Gant, 1969.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9914704773606533
Biography
Charles Green Gant was born on September 24, 1916 in Nashville, Tennessee; AB, Antioch College, 1942; moved to Washington, D.C. to be an administrative analyst with the U.S. Bureau of the Budget; in 1951 became comptroller, then Study Director for the National Science Foundation; became business manager of Lockheed Aircraft Corporation's research laboratories in Van Nuys, California; director of Philco-Ford Newport Beach operations until 1967; president, Northridge Democratic Club, 1958 and Santa Ana Democratic Club, 1960-61; served as California Democratic Council (CDC) director for the 35th congressional district, 1963-65; manager of 1964 CDC convention; elected as first southern vice-president of CDC in its 1965 reorganization, but resigned with other board members several months later because of insoluble conflicts with CDC president Simon Casady; helped form and then head Democrats of Southern California; elected in 1964 and continued to serve as member of Democratic County Central Committee of Orange County.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence, clippings, and printed material relating to the activities of the California Democratic Council and former southern vice-president, Charles G. Gant. Includes files on the Simon Casady political disputes, 1965, as well as materials related to Gant's political activities in Orange County, California.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
CDC board of directors meetings and minutes (Boxes 1-2).
CDC Bulletin (Box 3).
Simon Casady political disputes (Boxes 3-4).
CDC conventions, etc. (Box 5).
Election reform--NPAAC (Box 6).
Orange County Council of Democratic Clubs--Richards-Kuchel campaign, 1962 (Box 7).
35th congressional district--volunteer politics conference (Box 8).
Miscellaneous papers (Box 9).
Various campaign and political mementos.
Related Material
The California Democratic Council and grass-roots politics [oral history transcript] / Charles G. Gant, interviewee. UCLA Oral History Department interview, 1970. Available at UCLA Library Special Collections.
Tom B. Carvey papers (Collection 1110). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections.
Larry N. Gerston California Democratic Council Records (Collection 1281). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections.
Knox Mellon California Democratic Council Records (Collection 1061). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections.
California -- Politics and government -- 1951-.; Orange County (Calif.) -- Politics and government.; Political activists -- California, Southern.; California Democratic Council--Archives.; Gant, Charles G., 1916- --Archives.
- CDC Board of Directors Meetings and Minutes of Meetings, 1962-January 1965
  - Fresno., April 1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Long Beach., June 1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Asilomar., August 1962 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Santa Barbara., October 1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Fresno., December 1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Club meeting notices. (Box 1, Folder 5a)
  - Bakerfield., January 1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Sacramento., May 1963 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Santa Monica., June 1963 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Fresno., September 1963 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Fresno., November 1963 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Fresno., January 1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Fresno., April 1964 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Fresno., June 1964 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Palo Alto., September 1964 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - El Segundo., November 1964 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Fresno., January 1965 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- CDC Board of Directors Meetings and Minutes of Meetings, April 1965-November 1966
  Scope and Contents note
  [Several of the folders in this box include informal minutes of Executive Committee meetings, usually held prior to the Board meetings.]
  - Bakersfield., April 1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - San Francisco., June 1965 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Fresno., September 1965 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Los Angeles., October 1965 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Fresno., November 1965 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - San Francisco., April 1966 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Fresno., June 1966 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Santa Monica., September 1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Lake Tahoe., November 1966 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Board Meetings - Arrangements for the site locations., 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Includes correspondence.
- CDC Bulletin and Simon Casady Affair, 1962-1965
  - Bulletin., 1962 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    vol.1, no.1-11.
  - Bulletin., 1963 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    vol.2, no.1-10.
  - Bulletin., 1964 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    vol.3, no.1-9.
  - Bulletin., 1965 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    vol.4, no.1-4 [i.e., May].
  - [Simon] Casady Affair, 1965 (Box 3, Box 4)
    - Clippings. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence supporting Casady. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - General file. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - "Explanation of Charges Relating to the Competency of Simon Casady as President of the California Democratic Council"., October 1965; (16 leaves). (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Casady Aftermath., 1965 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Correspondence, clippings, etc. re the activities of CDC following the Casady Affair.
  - Casady Aftermath., 1966 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Champions of CDC. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Civic and Human Relations Committee., 1965 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence of Southern Vice-President (Gant) (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
    - April-June 1964. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - July-December 1965. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- CDC Conventions, etc.
  - Fresno., 1961 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Bakerfield., 1963 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Long Beach., 1964 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Commendatory letters re Long Beach convention., 1964 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Sacremento., 1965 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Sacremento Convention papers., 1965 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Convention, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 7-9)
    - Location plans and correspondence. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Aftermath. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Dollars for Democrats. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Election, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 10-13)
    - Clippings. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Democratic Campaign. (Box 5, Folder 11-12)
    - Primary Results. (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Election Reform - NPAAC
  - Election Reform. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Election Results., 1960-1966 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Primarily clippings.
  - Issues Program (Box 6, Folder 3-6)
    - 2nd Annual I.P., 1961 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - 3rd Annual I.P., 1961 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - 1963. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - 1966. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party., 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Negro Political Action Association of California., 1965 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Orange County Council of Democratic Clubs - Richards-Kuchel Campaign, 1962
  - Orange County Council of Democratic Clubs., ca. 1962-1965 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Organization Committee., 1965 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Political Action (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
    - Region I., 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - State., 1965 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Registration Campaign, Sample., 1968 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Resolutions Committee., 1965 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Richards - Kuchel Campaign for U.S. Senate., 1962 (Box 7, Folder 7-8)
- 35th Congressional District - Volunteer Politics Conference
  - 35th Congressional District - CDC Director's Affairs. (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
    - 1963. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - 1964. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - 1965. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Volunteer Politics Conference, Atlantic City., 1964 (Box 8, Folder 4-7)
  - 1 large photograph. (Box 8)
- Miscellaneous papers
  - CDC papers (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
    - 1960-1963. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - 1966-1967. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - CDC Publications. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Journal of CDC. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    vol.2, no.1 and vol.23, no.1.
  - Democratic campaign literature, various campaigns., Various years (Box 9, Folder 5-6)
  - Miscellaneous papers and fragments. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous publications. (Box 9, Folder 8-9)
  - Various campaign and political mementoes; a few miscellaneous printed items re Laguna Beach's Festival of Arts. (Box 10)